曾经有过一段时光
There was a time above...
那时候
A time before...
一切都很完美
There were perfect things.
犹若钻石
Diamond absolutes.
但是世间万物
How things fall.
都会陨落
Things on Earth.
而陨落了的一切
And what falls...
韦恩少爷
Master Wayne.
- 已然不复 - 布鲁斯
- ... is fallen. - Bruce!
布鲁斯 没事的
Bruce,it's all right
布鲁斯 别这样
Bruce, please.
蝙蝠侠大战超人 正义黎明
终极版
玛莎
Martha.
在梦中 它们将我带向光明
In the dream they took me to the light.
一个美丽的谎言
A beautiful lie.
大都会
人类认识到了超人的存在
- 杰克 - 布鲁斯
- Jack. - Bruce.
杰克 听我说
Jack, listen to me.
我要你马上让所有人离开大楼
I want you to get everyone out of the building. Right now.
- 明白吗 - 天呐
- You understand? - My god.
远离窗户
Stay away from the windows!
快走 快 大家快走
Let's go. Come on, start moving now, people.
快走 老板要我们离开大楼
Let's go. The boss wants us out of the building.
都赶紧的
So, let's make it happen.
杰克 杰克
Jack. Jack!
对不起 所有线路正忙
We're sorry. All circuits are busy now.
请稍后再拨
Will you please try you call again later.
上帝
Heavenly god.
天堂与人间的创造者
Creator of heaven and earth.
宽恕我的灵魂吧
Have mercy on my soul.
杰克
JACK !!!
大家牵好手
Buddy hands.
让我看看 真棒
Everybody show me. Good job
大家快走
Come on, guys.
牵紧了
Hold on tight.
快走
Come on, guys.
去吧
Go.
韦恩先生 韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne! Mr. Wayne!
我的腿没知觉了
I can't feel my legs.
- 我的腿没知觉了 - 我们这里需要人帮忙
- I can't feel my legs. - We need help over here!
帮帮我 我的腿没知觉了
Help me. I can't feel my legs.
你会没事的 听见没
You're going to be okay, you hear me?
沃莱士 他们怎么叫你的 沃利?
Wallace. What do they call you, Wally?
老板 你说了算
You're the boss, Boss.
好了
Alright.
- 你会没事的 - 小心 小心
- You're going to be okay. - Easy, easy.
来
Come on.
天呐 我的腿没知觉了
Oh my god. I can't feel my legs.
我的腿没...没知觉了
I can't... I can't feel my legs.
没事的 你会没事的
It's okay. You're going to be okay.
你没事的 好吗
You're okay, alright?
好了 听我说 我们会找到你妈妈的
Okay, you know what? We're going to find your mom.
她在哪
Where is she?
18个月后
印度洋某处
这样的风都不吉利
All that wind is bad luck.
是血染长空之兆
Blood in the sky.
她到了
There she is.
非洲 内罗米
莱恩小姐
Miss Lane.
莱恩小姐 我是杰米·奥尔森 摄像师
Miss Lane. Jimmy Olsen, photographer.
- 显而易见 - 希伦在哪
- Obviously. - Where's Heeron?
没能过境
Uh. Trouble at the border.
你怎么获得许可的
So uh. How'd you land it?
这还是头一回啊 阿玛迦可从不接受采访
This is like pioneer stuff. Amajagh has never given an interview.
你知道希伦跟我一起出任务时总说什么吗
You know what Heeron always says when we are on assignment together?
她都是闭嘴的
Not a god damn thing.
我喜欢希伦
I like Heron.
走吧
Let's go.
护照 电子器件 手机 相机
Passports, electronics, phones, camera.
你们接头的人说将军准许拍照
Your fixer said that the General approved photos.
你是恐怖分子吗 将军
Are you a terrorist, general?
他们没告诉我做采访的是位女士
They did not tell me the interview was with a lady.
我不是女士 我是记者
I'm not a lady, I'm a journalist.
我这个人 什么都没有
What I am, is a man with nothing,
只有对我人民的爱
except a love of my people.
这些雇佣兵的开销是谁出的 将军
Who's paying for these security contractors, general?
夜晚在我们头上飞过的无人机又是谁出的钱
Who pays for the drones that passed over our heads at night?
一个问题总会引发另一个问题
One question begs another.
对吗
Yes?
你要说什么 将军
So what you're saying, General.
它只是台相机
It's just a camera.
美国已声明在你们国家的内战中
The United States has declared it's neutrality
保持中立 无论是政策上还是原则上
in your country's civil war, both in policy and in principle.
别打开...
Oh, don't open...
被你曝光了
You just exposed...
这些虚伪的美式假话 说得像真理似的
These pious American fictions...spoken like truth.
好吧 那是我的胶卷 我...
Okay, that's my film. I...
拥有权力的人既不会遵从
Men with power obey neither
政策 也不会遵从原则 莱恩小姐
policy nor principle , Miss Lane.
谁都一样
No one is different.
没人是中立的
No one... is neutral.
中情局
CIA.
他们在追踪我们
They're tracking us.
你是中情局的
You're CIA.
- 什么 不是 不是的 - 你把他带了过来
- What?No,no! - You brought him here.
不是 他是个摄像师
No!He's a photographer
不
No!
跟她无关
我们只是用她的身份做掩护
她什么都不知道
没事的 露易丝
It's okay, Lois.
将军 这事有解决的办法
我已被授权提议
利爪死了 长官
Talon's down, sir.
蟒蛇 我们失去了在场的线人 重复 我们失去了在场的线人
Python, we've lost our asset on the ground. Repeat, we've lost our asset on the ground.
那个围场里还有平民 我们要救她出来
There's still civilians in the compound. We'll extract her.
不行 无人机即将进攻
Negative. Rpa to engage.
中止任务 然后藏好
Stand down and get black.
爆炸区会有友军 所以...
Well, there'll be friendlies in the blast zone. So...
取消那该死的无人机
Call off the god damn drone.
中止任务 这是命令
Stand down is an order.
- 蟒蛇 - 行动
- Python. - Let's move.
我...
I...
我并不知道
I didn't know.
无知和无辜
Ignorance is not the same...
可不一样 莱恩小姐
as innocence. Miss Lane.
起来
Get up!
站起来
Stand up!
快点 他要来了
Quickly, he's coming.
还有两分钟到达
Inbound, 2 Mikes.
即将飞过蟒蛇 飞过
Passing Python... Now.
收队
Move out!
- 目标已锁定 - 你可以开火了
- Target locked. - You are clear to engage.
导弹就绪 已在射程内
Armed hot and in range.
三
Three.
二
Two.
一
One.
通讯连接被击毁了
Link's been hit.
被什么击毁的
By what?
你再走一步 就看她脑袋开花吧
Take one step, you will see the inside of her head.
村子里的女人们听到一种声音
The women in the village heard a noise.
就像天空裂开了似的
Like the sky cracked open.
他飞下来
He came down,
然后发生了交火
then came fire.
芬奇议员
后来的事更可怕
Even worse came after.
芬奇议员
政府进攻了
The government attacked.
在村中毫无怜悯可言
No mercy in the villages.
我的父母都没能逃过此劫
My parents tried to run.
全世界都只关注超人能做什么
The world has been so caught up with what Superman can do,
却没人问他应该做什么
that... no one has asked what he should do.
委员会将依此记录向他追责
Let the record show that this committee holds him responsible.
他绝不会回应你们
He'll never answer to you.
他不会回应任何人
He answers to no one.
我想 甚至都不会回应上帝
Not even I think, to god.
58比0
58 to nothing.
大都会再次打爆了哥谭
Metropolis, again, blowing out Gotham city.
讲真 只有死忠球迷还在看台上了
Really, only the diehards are left in the stands.
DC27 接到报警 哈勃威街1939号的空屋里
Delta Charlie 27. Reports of screams coming from vacant home
有尖叫声传出
at 1939 harborway.
汤姆 和你合作很棒
Tom, it's been great working with you.
大都会州立大学队:58         哥谭城市大学队:0
我要感谢我们的监制和导播
I want to thank our producer and director.
- 等下 - 我都不想指出...
- Now wait a second. - I don't even want to suggest...
DC27 请回答
Delta Charlie 27, respond.
单跪结束进攻吧
Just take a knee.
他们排成一排了 克拉克森似乎要扔远球
They're lining up as if Clarkson is gonna throw it deep here.
- 不会吧 戴夫 - 要扔往端区了
- Don't tell me, Dave. - Going to the end zone!
- 真没必要这样 - DC27
- This is unnecessary. - Delta Charlie 27
齐克·贝克有空档 贝克触底接球得分
Zeke Baker is open! Baker with a touch down catch.
不敢相信 我竟目睹了这一幕
I can't believe I just watched that.
DC27 收到没
Delta Charlie 27. Do you copy?
收到 我们这就去
10- 4, we're on it.
现在爆发了斗殴
And now a fight breaks out.
你知道哥谭市民是怎么看他们的橄榄球队的
Gotham City, you know how they are about their football team.
大学橄榄球赛
今晚这座城市不会太平
Things could get ugly in the city tonight.
末日将至
哥谭海港
上
Go.
它救了我们
一个魔鬼
没事了
It's okay.
没事了 我们会帮忙
It's okay. We're-We're going to help.
我们是来帮忙的
We're here to help.
它救了我们
好了 我们带你们出去
Okay, we're going to get you out of here.
好吗
Okay?
它还在这里
我...我听不懂
I - I don't understand.
请住手 请住手
Please don't. Please don't.
求你了
Please.
我不知道他是谁
I don't know who he is.
不要
No!
该死
Fuck.
天呐
Christ!
我看到他了
I saw him.
我以前从没看到过 我不知道...
I never saw him before. I didn't know...
你差点打烂我的脸
You almost took my face off!
能别朝好人开枪吗
How about you don't shoot the good guys, huh?
天呐
Jesus Christ.
他给他烙了印
He branded him.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
我本想做饭呢 先给你个惊喜
I was going to cook. Surprise you.
他们就发生的事举行了听证会
They held hearings about what happened.
- 他们都在说... - 我不在乎
- They're saying that... - I don't care.
我不在乎他们说什么
I don't care what they're saying.
我爱的女人差点被炸或中枪
The woman I love could have been blown up or shot
- 想想可能的后果吧 - 想想已有的后果吧
- Think of what could have happened. - Well, think about what did happen.
那些人不是我杀的 如果他们是那么想的话
I didn't kill those men if that's what they think.
如果你是那意思的话
If that's what you're saying?
我意思是我想搞清楚发生了什么
I'm saying I want to understand what happened.
我意思谢谢你救了我的命
I'm saying, thank you for saving my life.
我想说这是有代价的
I'm saying there's a cost.
我只是不知道可不可能
I just don't know if it's possible.
不知道什么可不可能
Don't know what's possible?
爱我的同时 做你自己
For you to love me and be you.
克拉克 你会把公寓淹了的
Clark, you're going to flood the apartment.
你还在工作?
You still working?
阿尔弗雷德 你老了 手脚也慢了
You're getting slow in your old age, Alfred.
谁都会老 韦恩老爷
It comes to us all, master Wayne.
即便你老得没机会英年早逝了
Even you got too old to die young,
你也没少为之尝试
and not for lack of trying.
烟囱渡轮黄油块 烟囱渡轮黄油块
Funnel-ferry butterbar. Funnel-ferry butterbar.
烟囱渡轮黄油块 烟囱渡轮...
Funnel-ferry butterbar. Funnel-ferry...
麦克风没问题
There's nothing wrong with the microphone.
有问题的是装甲的新护层
It's this new layer of armor.
我只能重新装线了
I'll just have to rewire.
那么
So...
昨晚有收获吗
Last night was productive?
没
Nope.
他级别太低 什么都不知道
He's too low level, he knew nothing.
这个人倒知道些事
This is a man who knows things.
阿纳托里·肯亚佐夫 他是俄国人
Anatoli Knyazev. He's Russian.
生意遍布全球 但他的基地就在哥谭港口
Contracts all over the globe but he's base out of the port of Gotham.
贩卖武器和人口
Weapons and human trafficking.
所以理论上来说 白葡萄牙人是个俄国人
So, the "White Portuguese" is a Russian, that's the theory.
不
No.
理论上来说 顺着俄国人这条线 我能找到那个人
The theory is that the Russian lead me to the man himself.
如果他真的是个人
If he is indeed a him.
你都不知道他是否存在 他可能是个幻影
You don't even know if he exist. He could be a phantasm.
幻影会想把一枚脏弹带进哥谭?
One that wants to bring a dirty bomb into Gotham?
那太危险了
Ah, high-stakes round.
正义的蝙蝠烙印
哥谭自由报
新准则啊
New rules.
我们是罪犯 阿尔弗雷德
We're criminals, Alfred.
我们一直是罪犯 从没变过
We've always been criminals, nothing's changed.
已经变了 先生
Yes it has, sir.
一切都已经变了
Everything's changed.
有人从天而降
Men fall from the sky.
诸神掷下雷电
and gods hurl thunderbolts.
无辜者丧命
Innocents die.
改变就是这么开始的 先生
That's how it starts,sir.
狂热 愤怒 无能为力的感觉
The fever, the rage, the feeling of... powerlessness
把好人变得
that turns good men...
残暴
cruel.
约翰 防守
John, get d.
我不知道你们来了
I did not know you were here.
- 这就是招牌上的那个人啊 - 别当真
- Man on the marquee. - Stop, don't believe it.
我父亲用他的名字命名了公司 他才是集团二字前的莱克斯
My father named the company after himself. He was the Lex in front of the Corp.
- 嗨 你好吗 - 好极了
- Hi, how are you doing? - Oh, really great.
好极了?不错 不错
Really great? Good. Good.
跟我来
Uh. Follow me.
我爸为了吸引投资人 就开始说
No, uh, Dad started saying that he named
他是用孩子的名字给公司命名的
the company after his kid at investor pitches.
那些老富婆 她们觉得这做法很可爱
Rich old ladies. They thought it was very cute, you know?
都说 为莱克斯开支票吧
"Write check for Lex."
我爸在东德出生
You know, Dad was born in east Germany.
他是吃变质饼干长大的
He grew up eating uh... stale crackers.
每隔一个周六 他就得列队行军
And every other Saturday, he had to march in a parade
向独裁者挥舞鲜花
and waved flowers at tyrants.
所以 我认为这是天意 他的儿子
So, I think it was providence that his son,
我 最终得到了这个
me, would end up with this.
我的一个大都会重建组员找到的
One of my rebuild Metropolis crews found it.
来自氪星人世界引擎的一个小纪念品
A little souvenir from the Kryptonian World Engine.
一块石头和国家安全有什么关系
What's a rock have to do with Homeland Security.
国家安全?
Homeland Security?
不 不 不 女士 是星球安全
No, no, no... ma'am. Planetary Security.
这个碎块是放射性外太空矿物
The fragment is of a radio active Xeno mineral
我们怀疑它或许有生物交互作用
We suspected it might have bio interactions,
所以 我们把样本给了陆军传染病医学研究所
so, we took the sample to amriid.
莱克斯集团
那里保留着氪星死者的遗体
Where they keep the remains of the Kryptonian decedent.
当我们将这个矿物接触佐德将军时
And, when we exposed general Zod to the mineral,
发生了这样的情况
this happened.
强烈的生物降解作用 ​​在衰变氪星人的细胞
Profound biodegradation, decaying Kryptonian cells.
我们断定 如果找到一个足够大的样本 就能武器化这种矿物
We concluded the mineral could be weaponized, if a large enough sample was found.
后来 在鱼群中 一个大家伙
And then, among the fishes, a whale!
躺在印度洋的海底
Lying at the bottom of the Indian Ocean
犹如翡翠城
Emerald City.
美极了
Beautiful.
这大石头有放射性
Now, Rocky is radio active, but,
需要你们的一张进口许可证
what he needs from you is an import license.
我们为什么要武器化这种物质
And why would we want to weaponize this material?
用来威慑 预备一颗银弹
As a deterrent. A silver bullet to keep in reserve
来对付氪星人 女士 这样你的后辈
to use against the Kryptonians. So, the day doesn't come, Madame,
在检阅台上挥舞雏菊的日子就不会到来
when your children are waving daisies at a reviewing stand.
据我所知 那些氪星人中
Last I looked, the only one of those
还在天上飞来飞去的只有超人
flying around up here was Superman.
没错 超人
Ha. Yes, Superman.
没错 但还有...还有更多这一类的
Yeah, but, there are... there are more of them.
- 超人类论 - 没错 超人类论
- The meta- human thesis. - Yes, the meta- human thesis.
这些超常之人很可能生活在我们之中
More likely than not. These exceptional beings live among us.
我们众多神话的基础 就是我们...
The bases of our myths. Gods among men upon our...
我们小蓝星上的人间诸神
our little blue planet here.
你不是非得用银弹
You don't have to use the silver bullet,
但是 如果铸造一颗
but, if you forge one...
那么
Well, then...
我们就不用依赖怪物们的仁善了
We don't have to depend upon the kindness of monsters.
我们能互相帮助
There're ways we can help each other.
到我这边的办公处来吧
Would you step into my office here?
好的
Yes!
你有什么需求
What's your wish list?
进入坠毁的氪星飞船残骸
Access to the wreck of the crashed Kryptonian ship.
成交
Done.
还要那个外星人的完整遗体 用于测试
The complete remains of the dead alien for testing.
你想要佐德的尸体?
You want Zod's body?
没错
Okay.
樱桃味的
It's cherry.
因为是时候
Because the time has come
让全世界听到另一种声音了
for the world to hear the other side of the story.
人们说这个超人是一位英雄 好吧 可又是谁的英雄呢
They say this Superman is a hero. Okay, but whose hero?
假如超人现在就在这里
If Superman were here, right now.
你想对他说什么
What would you want to say to him?
对他说 我的家人也有梦想
That my family too had dreams.
并看着他的双眼
To look him in his eye,
问他是如何判定
and ask him how he decides
哪些生命有价值
which lives count
哪些生命没有价值
and which ones do not?
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
超人阻止了导弹袭击
布鲁斯·韦恩营救员工
一男子被首席执行官从废墟中救出
先生 下来
Sir. Get down.
先生 我说了 下来 快点
Sir, I said, get down, now!
我们这里能要些支援吗
Can we get some backup here?
嘿 嘿 住手
Hey. Hey. Don't do it!
嘿
HEY!
露易丝 罪证化验室 三号线
Lois. Crime Lab, on 3.
我是莱恩
This is Lane.
肯特 今天你负责体育版
Kent, you're sports today.
我要你去哥谭 跟进橄榄球方面的消息
I want you to go over to Gotham, follow up on the football.
弱旅梦碎 哥谭与荣耀 相隔10码
"Underdog dreams dashed: Ten yards between Gotham and glory."
在哥谭自己当心点
Watch yourself over there at Gotham.
别让人抢了你的午餐钱
Don't let them take your lunch money.
嘿 你们在看这个吗
Hey. Are you guys watching this?
紧急救援人员在英雄公园周围快速设防
Emergency responders quickly created a precautionary perimeter around Heroes Park
同时将此男子从这座受人爱戴的纪念碑上带走
while they brought the man down from this beloved monument.
嫌疑人已被确认是沃莱士·弗农·基夫
The suspect has been identified as Wallace Vernon Keefe.
我为布鲁斯·韦恩工作 我为布鲁斯·韦恩工作
I work for Bruce Wayne! I work for Bruce Wayne!
他将受到故意破坏公物及拒捕的指控
There'll be arraign on charges of vandalism, resisting arrest
伪
神
并受到一项制造恐怖威胁的重罪指控
and a felony charge of making terrorist threats
这些将导致多达40年的监禁
that carries up to 40 years in prison.
可怜的蠢货
Poor son of a bitch.
大都会新闻8台报道
Metropolis news 8.
珍妮
Jenny.
头条
Headline:
对空中飞人的强烈好感结束了 问号
"End of love affair with man in the sky, question mark."
好的
Okay.
她在吗
Is she in?
她已经离开了
Oh, she's been gone.
她干什么了 警官
What'd she do, officer?
我不是警察 我是记者
Oh, I'm not a cop. I'm a reporter.
住这里的这位年轻女士...
The young lady living here...
她一直没回来
Uh, she hasn't been back.
她要是聪明 就已经离开这座城市了
In fact, if she's smart, then she's got out of this city.
而你得在天黑前离开这里
And you need to get out of here... before dark.
- 除非你想撞见他 - 别听他的鬼话
- Unless you want to run into him. - Don't listen to that nonsense.
只有那些做亏心事的人才害怕他
Only people scared of him, people who got reason to be.
害怕谁
Scared of who?
他的狠辣已不同往日
Well, there's a new kind of mean in him.
他很愤怒
He is angry.
他正在狩猎
And he's hunting.
让他们看看你的厉害
Show 'em what you got!
上啊 加油
Let's go!Come on!
快出拳
Throw a punch, will ya?
上啊 加油
Let's go! Come on!
谢谢
Thank you.
这地方把运气当成一种侮辱
The house treats luck like an insult.
一个人的好运总会是他兄弟的厄运
Good luck for one is always his brother's misfortune.
但所有的帐最后都要结平
和一个波修瓦剧院的芭蕾舞女共度了三晚 她只教了我这一句
3 nights with a Bolshoi ballerina, that line was all she taught me.
肯定不只这一句
Not all I'm sure.
晚上愉快
Good evening.
克隆设备成功
这是恐怖的独裁统治
It's like a one man reign of terror.
克隆设备成功
这个蝙蝠义警一直在盯着港口
This bat vigilante has been consistently targeting the port
还有邻近的工程和廉价公寓
and the adjacent projects and tenements.
在我看来 那些警察其实是在帮他
And as far as I can tell the cops are actually helping him.
哥谭的犯罪浪潮
"Crime wave in Gotham."
其他爆炸性新闻 水是湿的
Other breaking news: "Water, wet."
- 橄榄球的报道写好了吗 - 我们为什么不报道这个
- Did you file the football yet? - Why aren't we covering this?
因为穷人不买报纸?
Poor people don't buy papers?
人们都不买报纸了 就是这样 肯特
People don't buy papers, period, Kent.
佩里 你分派报道时 就是在选择谁重要
Perry, when you assign a story, you're making a choice about who matters.
- 谁值得 - 终于醒了啊 斯莫维尔土包
- and who's worth it. - Good morning, Smallville.
美国的良心已随罗伯特 马丁和约翰一起死了
The American conscience died with Robert, Martin and John.
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
没有匹配的
No match.
我在罪证化验室的人都没见过这个
My guys in the crime lab, never seen one before.
这叫子弹 开枪打人用的
It's called a bullet. You shoot people with them.
从沙漠的交火现场回收的
Recovered from the scene of the fire fight in the desert.
全世界任何地方都没有商业买卖 连黑市也没
Not sold anywhere commercially in the world, even black market.
所以?
So?
所以是谁把原型军用子弹给了在撒哈拉的图阿雷格战士
So, who gave prototype military rounds to tuareg fighters in the Sahara.
你是记者 你来告诉我
You are the reporter, tell me.
我认为美国政府在宣称支持民选政府的同时
I think the U.S government is arming the rebels
也在给反叛军提供武装
while claiming to support the elective government.
直接说想干嘛 露易丝
The ask, Lois.
今晚飞华盛顿 在那待几天
Flight to DC tonight, a couple of days there.
去吧
Go.
普通经济舱 不准选大空间座位
Coach. No extra leg room.
豪华经济舱
Economy plus.
普通经济舱
Coach.
你怎么没告诉我
So, why didn't you tell me?
你是在引蛇上身 小露
You're digging up snakes, Lo.
这有点危险
It's kinda dangerous.
所以我才没告诉你
That's why I didn't tell you.
莱恩 你不是要赶飞机吗
Lane, don't you have a plane to catch?
没错 头
Yes, sir.
大都会图书馆的公益活动
Benefit for the Library of Metropolis.
委员会有人请求克拉克·肯特报道这件事
Someone on the committee requested that Clark Kent cover it.
大概是某个做慈善的丑老太婆喜欢呆子
Probably some old charity crone has got a thing for nerds.
议员
Senator.
午餐前喝点波旁酒吗
Little bourbon before lunch?
我司机在外面 我不能久留
My driver's outside, I can't stay.
不喝波旁酒? 你这样的肯塔基姑娘竟然不喝?
No bourbon? A Kentucky girl like yourself?
我爸总说
My dad always said that,
肯塔基麦芽浆是健康的秘诀
Kentucky mash was the secret to health.
这曾是他的房间
This was his room.
我一直保持着原样
I kept it just the same.
我把一切都保持原样的话 或许有一天我爸会回来
"Maybe one day dad'll come back if I just keep everything the same."
这真傻
That is silly.
孤儿的妙想天开
The magical thinking of orphan boys.
我不会给你的矿物批准进口许可证
I'm blocking the import license for your mineral.
注:改自"The redcoats are coming"
美国独立战争期间 保罗·列维尔喊出的英军来袭警报
红披风要来了
The Red Capes are coming!
你和你听证会的人
You and your hearings.
在街上飞奔 来警告我们
Galloping through the streets to warn us.
注:改自亨利·沃兹沃斯·朗费罗的赞美诗《保罗·列维尔骑马来》
原为"One,if by land,two,if by sea"
从陆地来挂一盏灯 从天上来挂两盏灯
One, if by land. Two, if by air.
议员 你知道美国最古老的谎言吗
Do you know the oldest lie in America, Senator?
- 我能叫你琼吗 - 你喜欢怎么叫都行
- Can I call you June? - You can call me whatever you like.
也能把一桶尿叫做奶奶的蜜桃茶
Take a bucket of piss and call it Granny's peach tea.
把一件暗杀武器叫做威慑
Take a weapon of assassination and call it deterrence.
你骗不了我
You won't fool a fly on me.
我不会上当
I'm not going to drink it.
嘿 如果我就改变了这房里的
Hey, you don't think Dad would mind, do you?
一件东西
If I change just...
你觉得我爸是不会介意的吧
... just one thing in this room.
因为那东西应该是颠倒过来的
Because that should be upside-down.
现在我们更清楚了 对吗
Now, we know better now, don't we?
魔鬼并非来自我们下方的地狱
The devils don't come from hell beneath us. No.
他们来自天上
No, they come from the sky.
玛莎·韦恩
我希望韦恩家族的下一代不会继承一座空酒窖
I hope the next generation of Waynes won't inherit an empty wine cellar.
说得可能会有下一代似的
Not that there's likely to be a next generation.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
这是那个俄国人手机上打出的所有电话
This is every call made from the Russian's phone.
有两通提到了与白葡萄牙人的生意
Two mentions of business with the "White Portuguese" and
并且在继续向亚历山大·卢瑟的私人住所
it's continuing transmitting blacked-out data to the personal residence
传输隐蔽数据
of Alexandra Luthor.
你认为莱克斯·卢瑟就是白葡萄牙人?
You think Lex Luthor is the "White Portuguese"?
我看不出他需要进口武器来赚钱
I can't see that he needs the income from imported arms.
无论如何 我得在他的房子里放个窃录器
Regardless, I'll need to put a leech at his house,
我还需要战衣
and I'm going to need the suit.
蝙蝠审问了六个人 却一无所获
The Bat interrogated 6 people and came away with nothing.
是布鲁斯·韦恩搞到了信息
It was Bruce Wayne that got the information.
布鲁斯·韦恩可没法闯进莱克斯·卢瑟的房子
Well, Bruce Wayne can't break into Lex Luthor's house.
布鲁斯·韦恩不用闯进去
Bruce Wayne won't have to.
他已经被邀请了
He's been invited.
敬请参加
11月1日
晚上7点
由亚历山大·卢瑟举办
哈哈哈 你是个笑话 蝙蝠侠
- 拍张照 - 韦恩先生
- Have a shot. - Mr. Wayne!
这边
Over here.
那是谁
Who's that?
你一定没听过让他们吃蛋糕的梗
You must be new to the "let them eat cake" beat.
那是布鲁斯·韦恩
That is Bruce Wayne.
有请慈善家 藏书家
Philanthropist. Bibliophile.
大都会图书馆的真朋友 莱克斯·路瑟先生致辞
True friend of the Library of Metropolis. Mr. Lex Luthor.
我? 好吧
Me? Oh. Okay.
尼基
Nicky.
你让我为难了
You're embarrassing me.
演讲 演讲 这个那个
Speech. Speech. Uh, blah blah blah.
酒水免费
Open bar.
演讲结束
The end.
慈善家这个词 源于希腊文
The word "philanthropist" comes from the Greek.
意思是博爱之人
Meaning a lover of humanity
约2500年前被创造的
It was coined about 2,500 years ago...
好了 我要往哪走 阿尔弗雷德
Alright, where am I going, Alfred?
走过电梯 往左
Go past the elevator.Do a left.
没错 一定是
That's right, must be.
在地下室的服务通道
It's in the service corridor in the basement.
走下楼
Go down the stairs.
神明与人类之间
Gods and men.
普罗米修斯选择了我们
Prometheus went with us,
他破坏了宙斯毁灭人类的计划
and he ruined Zeus' plan to destroy man kind
为此 他遭到了雷劈
and for that, he was given a thunderbolt.
似乎很不公平
Hm. That seems unfair.
言归正传 大都会图书馆...
On the serious note, the Library of Metropolis...
走到你进来时看到的楼梯那 下楼
Go to the stairs. You saw them on your way in. Down the stairs.
但曾有一段时间 我爸买不了
But at one time, Dad could not buy them.
没错 我父亲小时候买不起书
No, My father could not afford books growing up.
他不得不从垃圾桶里翻出昨天的报纸
He had to root through the garbage for yesterday's newspaper.
好了 你右边是厨房
All right. You got the kitchens on your right.
往左
Do a left.
你前面 就是你要去的地方
Right in front of you, that's where you want to be.
需要帮忙吗 韦恩先生
May I help you, Mr. Wayne?
我只是...以为洗手间在这下面
Uh, I just... thought the bathroom was down here.
我一定是...
I must have...
最后一杯马提尼量太多了
That last Martini was two too many, I think.
- 男洗手间在楼上 - 太好了 我没事
- Men's room is upstairs. - Great, I'm okay.
我喜欢那双鞋
I like those shoes.
我不能待在下面 阿尔弗雷德
I can't stay down here, Alfred.
上楼交际去
Go upstairs and socialize.
找个大都会的年轻女士娶回家
Some young lady from Metropolis will make you honest.
别做梦了 阿尔弗雷德
In your dreams, Alfred.
书本就是知识 知识就是力量
Books are knowledge, and knowledge is power.
而我... 不...
And I am... Heh heh heh, no.
我...
I, umm.
不 我是什么 我在说什么呢
No, what am I? What was I saying?
不
No.
人苦乐参半的悲哀就在于有知识却无力量
The bittersweet pain among men is having knowledge with no power.
因为...
Because...
因为二者互相矛盾 还有...
Because that is paradoxical, and umm...
谢谢各位光临
Thank you for coming.
请尽情畅饮
Please drink. Drink.
韦恩先生 韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne. Mr. Wayne.
我是克拉克·肯特 星球日报的
Clark Kent, Daily Planet.
我的基金会已发布了支持图书公益的声明
Oh, my foundation has already issued a statement in support of books.
先生?
Sir?
美女一来 品行就败 别引用这句话 好吗
Pretty girl. Bad habit. Don't quote me, alright?
你对哥谭的蝙蝠义警持什么立场
What's your position on the bat vigilante in Gotham?
星球日报
Daily Planet.
等下 这是我旗下的 还是其他人的
Wait.Do I own this one? Or is that the other guy?
公民自由权已在你的城市中被践踏
Civil liberties has been trampled on in your city.
善良的人生活在恐惧之中
Good people living in fear.
不要相信你听到的一切流言 孩子
Don't believe everything you hear, son.
是我亲眼所见 韦恩先生
I've seen it, Mr. Wayne.
他认为他在法律之上
He thinks he's above the law.
星球日报竟在批评那些自认为在法律之上的人
The daily planet criticizing those who think they're above the law
有点虚伪啊 你不觉得吗
is a little hypocritical, wouldn't you say?
而每次你们的英雄从树上救下一只猫
Considering every time your hero saves a cat out of a tree,
你们就会写一篇吹捧的社论 来报道一个...
you write a puff piece editorial, about an alien who...
只要想摧毁整个星球 就能做到的外星人
if he wanted to, could burn the whole place down.
真到那时 我们做什么都无法阻止他
There wouldn't be a damn thing we can do to stop him.
世界上大多数人并不赞同你的看法 韦恩先生
Most of the world doesn't share your opinion, Mr. Wayne.
或许是我心中的哥谭市影响了我 我们只是...
Maybe it's the Gotham city in me, we just...
和穿得像小丑的怪胎们有过一段糟糕的历史
... have a bad history with freaks dressed like clowns.
伙计们 布鲁斯·韦恩和克拉克·肯特相见了
Boys! Mm, Bruce Wayne meets Clark Kent.
我喜欢 我喜欢把人们聚到一起
Ah, I love it! I love bringing people together!
- 你们好啊 - 莱克斯
- How are we? - Lex.
你好 很好 嗨 你好
Hello, good. Hi, hello.
我是莱克斯 幸会
Lex. It is a pleasure.
手劲真大
That is a good grip!
可别和这个人干架
You should not pick a fight with this person.
这么多年之后 我们终于把你请到大都会来了
So, after all these years, we've finally got you over to Metropolis.
- 我来是想喝光你的酒 - 千万别客气
- Well, I thought I'd come drink you dry. - Well, you're welcome.
不过你该常来港湾 我想带你看看我的实验室
You should hop the harbor more often, though.I'd love to show you my labs.
或许我们可以在某方面合作
Maybe we could partner on something.
我的研发部喜欢各种邪门歪道
My R&D is up to all sorts of no good.
传输完成
7分钟了
That's 7 minutes.
传输完成
看来传输完成了
Look likes the transfer's complete.
- 卢瑟先生 - 什么事
- Mr. Luthor. -  Yes?
- 是州长 - 州长
- The governor. - Governor.
- 失陪了 - 下次聊
- Excuse me. - Next time.
- 州长 嗨 - 莱克斯 很高兴见到你
- Governor, hi. - Lex, it's good to see you.
一场致命的工厂大火打断了华雷斯的亡灵节庆典
打扰下
Excuse me.
我不敢相信 他们任由那可怜的女孩死去
我们 作为这个星球上的一个族群 一直在寻找一个救世主
We, as a population on this planet, have been looking for a savior.
90％的人都信仰神力
90% of people believe in a higher power.
每一个宗教都信奉着某种救世主形象
And every religion believes in some sort messianic figure.
维克拉姆·甘地 纪录片导演 超人问题
当这个救世主角色真的来到地球时
And when this savior character actually comes to Earth,
我们要让他遵守我们的规则?
we want to make him abide by our rules?
我们必须明白 这是一个范式转变
We have to understand that this is a paradigm shift.
我们必须开始思考超越政治的东西
We have to start thinking beyond politics.
这个人身上有任何道德约束吗
Are there any moral constraints on this person?
我们有国际法
We have international law.
在这个地球上 每一个行为都是一种政治行为
On this Earth, every act is a political act.
安德鲁·苏利文 [ 畅销书作家 ] 超人的行为具有政治性
世界上最强大的人是一个有争议的人物
Is it really surprising, that the most powerful man in the world
这真的令人惊讶吗
should be a figure of controversy?
让一个个体参与国家事务
To have an individual engaging in the state level interventions
议员 琼·芬奇 肯塔基州(民主党)
这应该让我们深思
should give us all pause.
人类有一段可怕的过去 追随强权人物
Human beings have a horrible track record of following people with great power
并导致了严重的人类暴行
down paths that led to huge human atrocities.
格伦·伍德伯恩 海外博主
我们一直在以我们自己的形象创造崇拜对象
We have always created icons in our own image.
我们所做的就是把我们自己投射到他身上
What we've done is we project ourselves on to him.
事实是 也许他不是某种魔鬼或耶稣的角色
The fact is, maybe he's not some sort of devil or Jesus character.
也许他只是一个试图做正确之事的人
Maybe he's just a guy trying to do the right thing.
我们在谈论的是一个真实存在的生命体
We're talking about a being whose very existence
尼尔·德哥拉斯·泰森 天体物理学家 宇宙论者 作家
挑战了我们自身在宇宙中对优先级的认识
challenges our own sense of priority in the universe.
如果你追溯哥白尼 那时他重建了
If you go back to Copernicus, where he restored
已知的宇宙中心 用太阳取代了地球
the sun in the center of the known universe, displacing earth.
再看看达尔文的进化论
And you get to Darwinian evolution
就会发现 我们在地球上不是特殊的
and you find out, we're not special on this Earth
我们只是其他生命形式中的一种
we're just one among other life forms.
现在我们了解到 我们甚至在整个宇宙中都不是特殊的
And now we learned, that we're not even special in the entire universe
因为有超人
because there is Superman.
他就在那里 一个在我们之中的外星人
There he is. An alien among us.
我们并不孤单
We're not alone.
作为一名美国议员 你是说你能自在地
Are you, as a United State Senator, personally comfortable
亲自向一对悲伤的父母说 超人原本可以救你们的孩子
saying to a grieving parent, "Superman could've saved your child,
但原则上 我们不希望他采取行动?
but on principle we did not want him to act."?
我不是说他不该采取行动
I'm not saying he shouldn't act.
我是说他不该单方面采取行动
I'm saying he shouldn't act unilaterally.
那我们在这里讨论的是什么呢
What are we talking about here then?
是否必须要有一个超人?
Must there be a Superman?
已经有了
There is.
你好
Hello?
妈
Mom.
克拉克
Clark.
什么事 怎么了
What is it?What's wrong?
没事 我只是...
No,nothing.I just...
嗨
Hi.
爸爸怎么从没离开过堪萨斯
How come Dad never left Kansas?
他只是...
Well, he just...
你知道他是什么样的人
You know how he was.
而我要旅行干嘛呢 我已经旅行了
What do I need to travel for? I'm already there.
我只是希望事情能更简单些
I just wished it was more simple.
我的宝贝孩子
My baby boy.
没有什么事是简单的
Nothing was ever simple.
一个奇怪的小东西
An odd little duck.
我从没见过这样的金属
I've never seen a metal like this.
可能是国防部高级研究计划局的黑匣子
Could be darpa black box.
谁能搞清楚呢
Well, who could find out?
没人想搞清楚
Nobody who'd want to.
或许他们把这些给反叛军是为了做战地测试
Maybe they gave them out to the rebels to test in theater.
把活人士兵当实验动物用?
Using live soldiers as guinea pigs?
你之所以是个如此出色的记者
And this is what makes you such a good reporter.
是因为这种事还是会使你震惊
Stuff like this still shocks you.
对哥谭市的犯人们来说 蝙蝠烙印就是死刑判决
几十个罪犯被标上了蝙蝠烙印
被烙者在哥谭臭名昭著的黑门监狱有安全风险
蝙蝠侠在充当法官 陪审团及处刑人
哥谭身着披风的犯罪斗士是不是太过了呢
弄不掉了 弄不掉了
It don't come off!It don't come off!
移交囚犯
Prisoner transfer.
你不能把我关进普通牢房 老兄 他们会杀了我
You can't put me in general, man.  They gonna kill me.
嘿 你不能带我去普通牢房
Hey, you can't bring me to general.
你应该感谢大都会的纳税人们
You should be thanking the tax payers of Metropolis
收容你这被烙的混蛋
for taking in your branded ass.
- 请签字 - 我被标记了 老兄
- Sign in please. - I'm marked, man.
你知道他们对有这东西的人会做什么吗
You know what they do to people with this on them?
他只是个罪犯
He's only a criminal.
- 这边 快走 他们会杀了我
- This way! Let's go! - They're gonna kill me!
- 他们会杀了我 - 快走
- They're gonna kill me! - Let's go!
基夫 你被保释了 打开二号
Keefe, you made bail. Open Two.
谁出的钱
Who paid?
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
- 就是个人而已 - 是吗
- Just a man. - Yeah?
你他妈想干嘛
What the fuck you want?
帮你坐稳立场
To help you stand for something.
你三点的预约到了
Your 3 o'clock's here.
他让我成了一个不完整的男人
He made me half a man.
我妻子
My wife...
离开了我
...walked out on me.
我甚至不能站着小便
I can't even piss standing up.
让我对质他
Let me face him.
你会处理好吧?
You'll take care of it?
很好
Good.
怎么了
What?
退后 让开
Back up! Make a hole!
走错地方了 小姐
Wrong room, miss.
斯万维克部长 你一直没回我电话
Secretary Swanwick, you haven't been returning my phone calls.
莱恩小姐 如果你想采访 那扇门外面就能找到法里斯少校
Miss Lane, if you like an interview, Major Farris is just outside that door.
你把我当成陌生人?
You're treating me like a stranger?
我把你当成记者
I'm treating you like a reporter.
好吧
Alright.
美国在向非洲的反叛军提供实验性军用武器吗
Is the US providing experimental military arms to rebels in Africa?
你这么有胆量的人
You know with balls like yours.
应该属于这里
You belong in here.
你的消息来源是什么 锡箔帽吗
What's your source on this? A tin foil hat?
不是锡 是金属
No, not tin, but it's metal.
在那次超人事件中射出的 五角大楼的专家都无法识别它
Fired in the Superman incident. Experts at the Pentagon can't ID it.
- 我们没有被告知真相 - 真相就是
- We haven't been told the truth. - Here's the truth.
一名记者贪求独家新闻 去了她不该去的地方
A reporter got greedy for a scoop and went where she shouldn't have.
超人救她时 就像兵痞似的 还导致了多人死亡
Superman acted like some... rogue combatant to rescue her and people died.
不要用编造阴谋论来放回他的圣环
Don't invent a conspiracy theory to put back his halo.
或你的圣环
Or yours.
- 少校 - 长官
- Major. - Sir.
我登录了你的网盘找复件
So, I logged into your drop box to find a copy.
找到了这个复件
There's a copy, alright.
但却没有关于橄榄球的 没有关于...
But, nothing about football. Nothing about...
大都会图书馆的那些朋友的 只有...
Friends of the Metropolis Library, just...
该死的哥谭蝙蝠的事 我跟你说了别追
The god damn Gotham bat thing, I told you not to pursue.
警方不会帮忙 媒体不得不做正确的事
The police won't help, the press has to do the right thing.
轮不到你来决定是什么正确的
You don't get to decide what the right thing is.
星球报社成立时 是有立场的 佩里
When the Planet was founded, it stood for something, Perry.
1938年时 的确如此 但现在不是1938年
So could you, if it was 1938, but it's not 1938.
公共事业振兴署不再雇人了 一堆苹果也不再只值几分钱
WPA aren't hiring no more. Apples don't cost a nickel.
这里不准追 外面也不准 放掉这件事
Not in here. Not out there. You drop this thing.
没人在意克拉克·肯特叫板蝙蝠侠
Nobody cares about Clark Kent taking on the Batman.
所以很显然 超人
So apparently superman
不再希望我们把他当成美国人
doesn't want us to think of him as American anymore.
说真的 我们何必呢
And really, why would we?
我意思是除了那身红蓝服装 还有...
I mean aside from the red and blue costume. And...
怎么说呢 美利坚合众国的
I don't know, the fact that he has
英文缩写 有三分之一都在他的胸口上了
one-third of the usa's initials on his chest.
我猜他没有把独立宣言
I assume the only reason he's not wearing
当披风来穿的唯一原因就是...
the declaration of independence as a cape is...
他觉得这样做太招摇了
He thinks it's too on- the- nose.
- 这里在搞什么 - 不好
- What is going on back here? - No.
伙计们 快点 走了
Guys, come on. Let's go.
打起精神 快出去
Get yourselves together and get out there.
把那些玻璃杯都放托盘上
Get those glasses on those trays.
外面有客人口渴着呢
We got thirsty people out there.
半满 记住 半满
Half full. Remember, half full.
我们能失陪一下吗
I wonder, would you excuse us?
- 我想带你看样东西 - 抱歉
- There's something I'd like to show you. - I'm sorry.
现在有些学者坚持认为那件事从没发生过...
Now some scholars insist that it never happened...
但我相信那种行为
But I believe it's the action
完全符合一个既是国王又是变态杀手的人
perfectly in keeping with a king who was also a psychopathic killer.
对我而言 这是40年策展的巅峰
For me, it's the culmination of 40 years curating.
我简直不敢相信 我终于把它弄来了
And I can't believe it, but I've finally got it here.
它就是亚历山大之剑
It's the sword of Alexander.
砍断戈尔迪之结的那把剑
It's the blade that cut the gordian knot.
这是场胜利
It's a triumph.
的确
Yes.
- 请尽兴 - 谢谢
- Enjoy. - Thank you.
这是一件赝品
It's a fake.
真品在98年时在黑市上被卖了
The real one was sold in '98 on the black market.
现在它挂在...
And now it hangs...
挂在哈杰尔苏丹的床头
Over the bed of the sultan of hajar.
失陪了
Excuse me.
不好意思 小姐
Excuse me, miss.
前几天晚上 你拿了不属于你的东西
The other night you took something that doesn't belong to you.
偷是没教养的
Stealing's not polite.
如果从另一个小偷那儿偷 也算偷吗
Is it stealing if you steal from another thief?
你是什么人
Who are you?
某个和你关注同一个人的人
Someone interested in the same man you are.
是吗
Is that right?
我相信卢瑟先生有一张属于我的照片
I believe Mr. Luthor has a photograph that belongs to me.
你拿到了吗
Did you get it?
事实上 没 我没拿到
As it happens, no, I didn't.
你复制的数据都有军工级加密
The data you copied has military- grade encryption.
我用你这身礼服打赌
You know, i bet with that dress,
十个男人里有九个愿意让你顺走任何东西
9 out of 10 men will let you get away with anything.
但你是那第十个?
But you're the 10th?
我想我是第一个
I'm guessing I'm the first
看穿你那低幼把戏的男人
to see through that babe-in-the-woods act.
你不了解我
You don't know me,
但我认识几个你这样的女人
but I've known a few women like you.
我可不觉得你见过我这样的女人
Oh, I don't think you've ever known a woman like me.
人们对于小男孩的说法一点没错
You know, it's true what they say about little boys.
天生不会分享
Born with no natural inclination to share.
我没偷你的硬盘
I didn't steal your drive.
我只是借用
I borrowed it.
你会在你车上的储物箱里找到它的
You'll find it in the glove compartment of your car.
再见 韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne.
你们拿到了吗
Did you get it?
那块石头
The rock?
我们拿到了
Yeah, we got it.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
蹲下 快蹲下
Get down! Get down now!
不
No!
她是我的世界
She was my world.
而你把她从我这夺走了
And you took her from me.
布鲁斯
Bruce!
布鲁斯 现在听我说
Bruce! Listen to me now!
是露易丝
It's Lois!
是露易丝·莱恩
It's Lois Lane!
她是关键
She's the key!
我来太早了吗
Am I too soon?
我来太早了
I'm too soon!
你对他的看法没错
You're right about him!
你对他的看法一直是对的
You've always been right about him!
警惕他 警惕他
Fear him! Fear him!
找到我们 布鲁斯
Find us, Bruce!
你必须找到我们
You have to find us!
哥谭自由报
蝙蝠烙印下的正义
人贩被烙上蝙蝠侠的标记
法官
陪审团
处刑人
正义?
白葡萄牙人不是一个人
The white Portuguese is not a man.
而是一艘船
It's a ship.
韦恩老爷 你从七岁起
Master Wayne, since the age of seven
对骗术的掌握就好比
you have been to the art of deception
莫扎特之于大键琴一般高超
as Mozart to the harpsichord.
但你从来都不善于对我撒谎
But you've never been too hot at lying to me.
白葡萄牙人装载的不是脏弹
The white Portuguese is not carrying a dirty bomb.
装载的是什么
What is it carrying?
一件武器
It's a weapon.
是一块石头
It's a rock.
一种能让氪星人细胞衰弱的矿物
A mineral capable of weakening Kryptonian cells.
三个月前 第一块足够大到有用的样本
The first sample big enough to mean something
出现在了印度洋中
turned up in the Indian ocean three months ago.
它现在在白葡萄牙人上
It is now aboard the white Portuguese
被送到莱克斯·卢瑟那里
being delivered to Lex Luthor.
而我要从他那里偷走它
Who I am going to steal it from.
为了不让它落到卢瑟手里
To keep it out of Luthor's hands.
为了摧毁它
To destroy it.
不是
No.
你是要开战?
You're gonna go to war?
那个混蛋两年前就给我们带来了战争
That son of a bitch brought the war to us two years ago.
天呐 阿尔弗雷德 数数死亡人数吧 有上千人啊
Jesus, Alfred. Count the dead. Thousands of people.
接下来呢 上百万吗
What's next? Millions?
他拥有抹去整个人类的力量
He has the power to wipe out the entire human race,
哪怕我们认为他只有1%的可能是我们的敌人
and if we believe there's even a 1% chance that he is our enemy,
我们都必须把这可能性当成绝对的
we have to take it as an absolute certainty.
我们必须消灭他
And we have to destroy him.
但他不是我们的敌人
But he is not our enemy.
今天不是
Not today.
阿尔弗雷德 哥谭这20年间
20 years in Gotham, Alfred.
我们都见识了承诺的分量
We've seen what promises are worth.
还剩多少善良的人
How many good guys are left.
又有多少人一直如此
How many stayed that way.
给你14个小时
14 hours.
我叫克拉克·肯特 来自星球日报
My name is Clark Kent. I'm from the daily planet.
我想了解一个叫桑托斯的囚犯发生了什么事
I'm trying to find out what happened to an inmate, a Santos.
我不能对外公布这个信息
I can't give out that information.
蝙蝠来了
妈妈
Mommy!
桑托斯夫人
Mrs. Santos?
我能问你几个问题吗
May I ask you a few questions?
他不是我的丈夫
He wasn't my husband.
但我知道他干了什么
But I know what he did.
但他是一个父亲
But he was a father.
他也身为人父
He was that, too.
他们把他带离哥谭中央警署
They took him out of Gotham central.
把他转移到了大都会
They moved him to Metropolis.
但他们心里清楚
But inside they know.
他们完全清楚那个标记 可警卫不管
They know the mark all over. Guards don't care.
蝙蝠就是法官
Bat's the judge.
一个决定谁生谁死的人
One man decides who lives.
- 那样的正义算什么 - 跟我说说
- How is that justice? - Talk to me.
- 帮我来改变它 - 用什么 你的笔吗
- Help me change it. - With what? Your pen?
他那种人 没法用文字阻止
A man like that, words don't stop him.
你知道什么能阻止他吗
You know what stops him?
拳头
A fist.
肯特 我要和你谈谈
Kent, I want to talk to you.
肯特
Kent!
他去哪了 珍妮 他去哪了
Where does he go? Where does he go, Jenny?
我不...我不知道
I don't... I don't know.
注:改自小说《绿野仙踪》中的句子
原是桃乐丝将其鞋跟互碰三下就能回老家
鞋跟互碰了三次
Clicks his heels three times,
回堪萨斯去了吧
goes back to Kansas, i suppose.
混...
Son of a...
放
Turn it!
收队
Move out!
快开 快开 快开 快开
Go, go, go, go!
不
No!
他在哪
Where is he?
他们下次再用你的灯照耀天空
Next time they shine your light in the sky,
别去了
don't go to it.
蝙蝠已经死了 埋了它吧
The bat is dead. Bury it.
就当是我手下留情
Consider this mercy.
告诉我
Tell me.
你会流血吗
Do you bleed?
你会的
You will.
莱克斯集团研究园
我头上可没圣环 部长先生
I don't have a halo over me, Mr. secretary.
我去了沙漠 那里有人死了
I went into the desert, people died.
这让我难以入睡 这是当然的
It keeps me awake. It should.
如果你认为超人是凶手
If you think that superman is a murderer,
那就把它扔了吧
then throw it away.
但我相信你不那么认为
But I don't believe you think that.
我们如何确定什么是善意呢
How do we determine what's good?
在民主国家 善意就是沟通交流
In a democracy, good is a conversation,
而非单方面的决定
not a unilateral decision.
所以我敦促超人
So I urge superman to come
明天到这座人民之山来
to this hill of the people tomorrow
芬奇议员新闻发布会
看看那些遭受了痛苦的人
to see those who have suffered.
芬奇议员新闻发布会
世界需要知道在那片沙漠中发生了什么
The world needs to know what happened in that desert.
需要知道他的立场
And to know what he stands for.
他会将他的力量用到哪种程度
How far will he take his power?
他是根据我们的意志行事 还是根据他自己的意志
Does he act by our will or by his own?
人们讨厌他们不理解的东西
People hate what they don't understand.
但他们看见你的所作所为 就会了解你
But they see what you do, and they know who you are.
你不是杀手 也不是威胁
You're not a killer, a threat.
我从来都不希望这个世界拥有你
I never wanted this world to have you.
做他们的英雄 克拉克 做他们的丰碑
Be their hero, Clark. Be their monument.
做他们的天使
Be their angel.
做他们需要你做的
Be anything they need you to be.
或者什么都不做
Or be none of it.
你不欠这世界任何东西
You don't owe this world a thing.
从来都不欠
You never did.
德尼罗斯到了 可换乘至凯恩大道
This is deniros. Transfer available to Kane Avenue.
请当心脚下
Please, mind your step.
今天我必须跟议员谈话
I have to speak to the senator today.
今天你不能见议员
You cannot see the senator today.
我需要在听证会之前跟她谈话
I need to speak to her before the hearing.
你明白这有多重要吗
Do you understand how important this is?
我不能让你见议员
I cannot let you see the senator.
求你了 我得跟她说话
Please, I need to speak to her.
求你了 女士 我求你了 请别这样
Please, madam. I beg of you! Please don't do this!
这十分重要
This is so important!
- 跟我来 - 别碰我
- Come with me. - Don't touch me!
- 求你了 - 对不起 她不肯走
- Please! - I'm sorry. She wouldn't leave.
我没告诉你真相
I didn't tell you the truth.
中情局认为沙漠那件事是个圈套
C.I.A Thinks the desert was a setup.
有人想加罪于超人
Somebody wanted superman to look guilty.
那子弹呢
The bullet?
那种金属是一家私人公司开发的
The metal was developed by a private company.
什么公司
What company?
莱克斯集团
Lexcorp.
莱克斯·卢瑟?
Lex Luthor?
他还在那个沙漠围场安插了他的私人雇佣兵
He also had private security contractors at the desert compound.
公开出来
Go on record.
绝不可能 这是机密
Not a chance. It's classified.
我又恰好喜欢我的工作
I happen to like my job.
这说不通
It doesn't make sense.
你说那个圈套是为了陷害超人
You said that the ambush was arranged to frame superman,
但他们怎么会知道他会出现在...
but how could they know that he'd show up in the...
那片沙漠中 谢谢
In the middle of the desert. Thank you.
好了 过来
Alright, come on through.
参议院听证会现在随时可能开始
The senate hearing is expected to get underway any minute now.
当然 最大的未知数就是
And of course the big unknown in all of this is
超人会出现吗
will superman show up?
这是他们真正所期盼的
That is what they're really waiting to see.
基夫先生 基夫先生
Mr. keefe. Mr. keefe.
我是索莉戴·奥伯莱恩 此刻栏目的
Soledad o'brien, in the moment.
问你个问题
Quick question for you.
你就要和议员们见面了
You're heading in to meet with the senators.
你会跟他们说什么
What will you tell them?
我是来告诉他们该醒醒了
I've come here to tell them to wake up.
这是血和肉的事实
This is flesh and blood.
他已经带来了一场战争
He has delivered a war here.
还有这个...
And this...
这就是战争的样貌
This is what war looks like.
我一无所有了
I have nothing.
先生 有很多人会说他是他们的英雄
There are plenty of people, sir, who would say he's their hero.
他不是英雄
He is not a hero.
格蕾丝 能麻烦你让格雷格上来吗
Grace, can you get Greg up here, please?
就现在
Right now.
一个匿名线人能证明每一件
An anonymous source can verify everything
我跟你所说在内罗米发生的事
I told you about what happened in nairomi.
- 一个匿名线人? - 刊登出来
- An anonymous source? Run it.
卢瑟策划了沙漠事件
Luthor engineered the desert.
那是给超人设的圈套
It was an ambush for superman.
相信你的记者 想想水门事件
Trust your reporter. Think Watergate.
好吧 你得想想打官司的事
Yeah, and you need to think litigate.
如果你是错的 卢瑟会把报社告到不复存在
If you're wrong, Luthor will sue the paper out of existence.
你需要证据
You need proof.
别这样 现在就得刊登出来
No. It needs to run now.
在听证会之前
Before the hearing.
如果超人知道了 或许会改变他的说辞
If superman knows, it might change what he says.
我不会拿报社冒险
I am not going to risk the paper
好让你在课堂上给你的救命恩人递纸条
so that you can pass notes in class to the man that rescued you.
他贿赂了她?
He paid her?
不只是贿赂了她 他还威胁了她
Not only paid her. He threatened her.
并给了她一份稿子熟记
Gave her a script to learn.
她父母在家里活得好好的
Her parents are alive back home.
不过那姑娘良心发现了
But the girl's got a conscience.
- 他一直在把委员会当他的木偶剧院来用 - 议员
- He's been using the committee as his puppet theater. - Senator!
嗨 你好
Hi, you.
别走开 我有话跟你说
Don't go anywhere. I want to talk to you.
梅茜 你先进去
Uh, you know what? Mercy, you go in
帮我占好座位
and make sure no one takes my seat.
你要干嘛
So what you been up to?
我只是来讲讲我的故事
I'm just here to tell my story.
那就是我想出资造一件威慑氪星人的武器
That I was willing to finance a Kryptonian deterrent,
但一位肯塔基的资浅议员
but a certain junior senator from Kentucky
决定要阻止
decided to block it.
没错 专议超人的委员会主席在安全问题上很手软
Yes, the chair of the committee on superman is soft on security.
- 格雷格 为什么他一直没收到我们的支票 - 他收到了 韦恩先生
- Greg, why hasn't he been getting our checks? - He is, Mr. Wayne.
他每个月都会收到一张受害人基金的支票
He gets a check from the victims fund every month.
可他都退回了
He returns them.
布鲁斯·韦恩
睁开你的双眼
...在两年前
...who lost both his legs
我是你的鬼魂
大都会的那些可怕事件中
in those horrific events in Metropolis
失去了他的双腿
that happened two years ago.
韦恩无胜算
绝不休战
天呐
Jesus.
我不会放过你
布鲁斯·韦恩 = 瞎子
为什么我从没看到过这些
Why haven't I seen this?
抱歉 我会查清楚的
I'm sorry. I'll get to the bottom of it.
他在那 超人来了
And there he is. Superman is here.
他真的来到了美国国会大厦
He is actually at the United States capitol.
这真的是一个历史性时刻
This is really a historic moment.
现在我们期望超人会
Now we expect that superman will give
向议员 向美国人民
some kind of a statement to the senate,
当然 还有向全世界 给出某种声明
to the American people, and, of course, to the world.
他在这里了 他来了
He's here. He came.
他在国会大厦上面
He's above the capitol. Ah.
待会儿里面的烫手山芋可不好接啊 小琼
You are gonna be on the hot seat in there, junebug.
我是在农场里长大的
I grew up on a farm.
猪我都斗得过
I know how to wrestle a pig.
你知道美国最古老的谎言吗 议员
Do you know the oldest lie in America, senator?
那就是 力量可以是无辜的
It's that power can be innocent.
祝你好运
Good luck.
小姐...
Oh, miss...
鲁迪 她能进去
Rudy, she's good to go.
超人=非法外星人
外星人不是美国人
这里是我们的世界 不是你的
滚吧
Get out!
- 滚吧 快滚 - 超人 超人
- Get out! Get out! - Superman! Superman!
今早又收到一封 韦恩先生
Another one came this morning, Mr. Wayne.
首先 我想感谢我们的证人
Let me say at the outset that I'm grateful to our witness
谢谢他今天来到我们面前
for coming before us today.
民主就是这么运作的
This is how a democracy works.
我们相互对话
We talk to each other.
我们经过民众的同意再行事 先生
We act by the consent of the governed, sir.
我以前坐在这里说过
I have sat here before to say
委员会是不会容忍暗箱操作的
that shadow interventions will not be tolerated by this committee.
也不会容忍谎言
Neither will lies.
因为今天是真相大白之日
Because today is a day for truth.
因为只有说出...
Because only by speaking...
只有携手合作 我们才能...
Only by working together can we...
才能...
Can we...
我们才能创造一个自由 以及...
Can we create a free, and a...
奶奶的蜜桃茶
莱克斯·卢瑟先生
莱克斯集团首席执行官
我的天
Oh, my god!
画面回到国会大厦
We're back at the nation's capitol,
此处出了大事
where something is happening.
你害死了你的家人
打扰一下
Excuse me.
打扰一下 警官
Excuse me, officer.
我是媒体人士 能麻烦你让我进去吗
Member of the press. Can you let me in, please?
慢慢深呼吸
Breathe slowly and deeply.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
谢谢 我需要点空间来工作
Thank you. I'm gonna need a little room to work.
女士 看来你的头部受伤了
Ma'am, it appears you've suffered a head injury.
请看着我手电的光
I'm gonna need you to follow my light with your eyes.
韦恩老爷
Master Wayne.
韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne!
...就在超人作证的参议院听证会大厅里
...in the senate hearing room where superman was testifying.
这是一起发生在国会大厦的灾难性事件
This is a catastrophic situation at our nation's capitol.
我们还没得到确切数字
We don't have exact numbers yet,
不过我可以告诉大家 已有十二个以上的人
but I can tell you that more than a dozen people
在这场爆炸中死亡
have died in this explosion.
急救人员已抵达现场
First responders are at the scene.
他们仍在救出受害者
They are still bringing victims out.
最初 超人也在爆炸后帮忙救出受害者
Now initially, superman was helping bring victims out after the blast
但他现在似乎消失了...
but he seems to have disappeared...
...引起了疑问
...raising questions.
卡丽·伯明翰在国会大厦现场为你报道
Carrie Birmingham, reporting live from the nation's capital.
国会警方现在已确认爆炸是由
Capitol police are now confirming that the blast was caused
听证会大厅里的一个爆炸装置造成的
by an explosive device inside the hearing room.
帮我再放一遍
Run that one more time for me.
- 能放大那个吗 - 好了 长官
- Can you enhance that? - There you go, sir.
国会警方向有线电视新闻网确认了
Capitol police are confirming to CNN
引爆炸弹的嫌疑犯是
that the suspected bomber is
沃莱士·维农·基夫 目前这些消息...
Wallace Vernon keefe. Now these sources...
克拉克 还是我 你能不能...
Clark, it's me again. Can you...
...可能是把爆炸装置藏在轮椅内
...could have gotten the explosive device into the hearing
带入听证会的
by concealing them inside his wheelchair.
至于超人 他当时在场
As for superman, he was in the room,
但显然没能阻止他
but obviously failed to stop him.
我没看见 小露
I didn't see it, lo.
我就站在那里 却没有看见
I was standing right there and I didn't see it.
克拉克 这件事有幕后主使
Clark, there are people behind this.
我没看见 恐怕是因为我就没看过
I'm afraid I didn't see it because I wasn't looking.
一直以来
All this time,
我都在按照我父亲的看法活着
I've been living my life the way my father saw it.
为一个鬼魂纠正错误
Righting wrongs for a ghost.
以为自己来到这里是为了行善
Thinking I'm here to do good.
超人一直都不是真实的
Superman was never real.
那只不过是一个堪萨斯农民的梦想
Just the dream of a farmer from Kansas.
对有些人来说 那个农民的梦想就是一切
That farmer's dream is all some people have.
是给了他们希望的一切
It's all that gives them hope.
这是有意义的
This means something.
在我的世界是有过
It did on my world.
可我的世界已不复存在
My world doesn't exist anymore.
欢迎
Welcome.
分析显示飞船在以37%的效能运转
Analysis reveals ship operating at 37% efficiency.
你是否要接管操作
Would you like to assume command?
是的
Yes, I would.
我要
很好 开始吧
Very well. Let's begin.
氪星的档案库包含了十万个不同世界的知识
The Kryptonian archive contains knowledge from 100,000 different worlds.
很好
Good.
教我吧
Teach me.
档案
超人类
2015年6月22日 上午10:13
法国 巴黎
比利时 1918年11月
亚历山大·卢瑟
Alexander Luthor,
已接受你的安全权限覆盖
your security override has been accepted.
创生室已准备分析基因样本
Genesis chamber ready to analyze genetic sample.
正在确认当前基因物质
Acknowledging presence of genetic material.
正在分析
Analyzing.
我已识别出基因主人身份为坎多城的佐德将军
I've identified the host as general Zod of Kandor.
正在确认当前外来基因物质
Acknowledging presence of foreign genetic material.
正在分析
Analyzing.
注:借用了希腊神话中伊卡洛斯的故事
你飞得太靠近太阳了
You flew too close to the sun.
看看你现在
Now look at you.
警告 此为禁止行为
Advising. Action forbidden.
氪星议会已颁布相应律法
It has been decreed by the council of Krypton
禁止任何人给如此面目可憎的
that none will ever again give life to a deformity
畸形体重注生命
so hateful to sight and memory.
那是无名的亵渎
The desecration without name.
那氪星议会在哪呢
And where is the council of Krypton?
被毁了 先生
Destroyed, sir.
那就继续吧
Then proceed.
好的 正在准备生物蛹并开始变形
Very well. Preparing chrysalis and commencing metamorphosis.
所以我们的疑问是
"And so we are left to wonder
如果超人注意到了危险而什么都没做
"if superman was aware of the threat and did nothing,
那他和此次国会大厦的惨剧有关系吗
"was he then complicit in the capitol tragedy?"
肯特还是没来?
Still no Kent?
他的消失引起了不少疑问
"His disappearance raises questions."
没来
No.
还有很多问题没有得到解答
There are still so many unanswered questions.
其中最主要的就是超人是否参与了
Chief among them, whether superman was involved
超人是否参与其中了?
此次袭击的谋划
in the planning of this attack.
超人是否参与其中了?
这是一个有着无限力量的个体
I mean, here's an individual who has unlimited power,
超人是否参与其中了?
却没去阻止离他只有几英尺的引爆者
yet did nothing to stop the bomber just a few feet away from him.
超人是否参与其中了?
这对调查员们来说 不合情理
It just doesn't add up for investigators.
烧死他 烧死他 烧死他
Burn him, burn him, burn him.
赌20美元 他没看见你
For twenty American, he didn't see you.
我也一样
Same for me.
他知道这山上不去
他是来送死的
援引当前一名熟悉此案的联调局官员
Now one FBI official familiar with this case
告诉我的原话
told me they found quote,
在基夫公寓里中了个大奖 发现了炸弹制造材料
"a jackpot of bomb-making materials inside keefe's apartment."
他们现在需要查明的是
What they need to determine now is
他是否在谋划与实行过程中得到了他人的协助
whether he had any help in the planning and execution of the bombing.
他们尚未排除
And they haven't ruled out the idea
超人是同谋的可能
that superman was a co-conspirator.
现在 我的线人们告诉我 他们在此事的调查中收到了
Now, my sources are telling me they are getting a barrage of anonymous and credible tips
大量匿名而又可靠的线索
with all roads in this investigation
全都指向了那位氪星来客
leading to the Kryptonian visitor.
好了 露易丝 你该走了
All right, Lois. You gotta go.
他并不知道自己会死
He didn't know he was gonna die.
他还买了不少食物
He just bought groceries.
那个轮椅和沙漠的那颗子弹
The wheelchair and the bullet from the desert
都由同种金属制成
were made from the same metal.
我知道 沙漠 听证会
I know. The desert. The hearing.
卢瑟想要超人所到之处都是死亡
Everywhere superman goes, Luthor wants death.
但是 卢瑟费了这么大劲
But, Luthor goes through all of that trouble...
把轮椅做成了一颗炸弹
Creates a bomb out of a wheelchair,
却又加以改造来降低爆炸威力?
and then alters it to reduce the blast?
什么意思
What do you mean?
轮椅内部衬了铅
The inside of the chair was lined with lead.
你没法阻止
You couldn't stop it.
你也看不见
You couldn't see it.
不错吧
Something, isn't it?
我们堪萨斯的人都生活在一个平原上
We men of Kansas live on a pancake,
所以我们要来山上
so we come to the mountains.
从这里往下 一直到漫滩
All downhill from here, down to the floodplain.
农场就在这世界的最低处
Farm at the bottom of the world.
我记得有一个时节的洪水很凶猛
I remember one season the water came bad.
那时我还不到12岁
I couldn't have been 12.
我爸拿出了铲子 我们拼命挖了一夜
Dad had out the shovels and we went at it all night.
一直到我晕了过去
We worked till, i think, I fainted.
但我们成功阻挡了洪水
But we managed to stop the water.
我们拯救了农场
We saved the farm.
你奶奶给我烤了个蛋糕 夸我是英雄
Your grandma baked me a cake. Said I was a hero.
那天晚些时候 我们发现
Later that day we found out
我们是挡住了洪水
we blocked the water all right.
可我们把它送回了上游
We sent it upstream.
朗家的整个农场都被冲走了
The whole lang farm washed away.
我在吃我的英雄蛋糕时 他们的马被淹了
While I ate my hero cake, their horses were drowning.
我以前常在睡梦中听见它们的嚎哭
I used to hear them wailing in my sleep.
这样的噩梦有停止过吗
Did the nightmares ever stop?
有
Yeah.
当我遇到你的母亲时
When I met your mother.
她让我相信这世界上还有美好存在
She gave me faith that there's good in this world.
她就是我的世界
She was my world.
我想你 儿子
I miss you, son.
我也想你 爸爸
I miss you too, dad.
你知道你赢不了的
You know you can't win this.
这是自杀
It's suicide.
我现在比我父亲死时的年纪还大
I'm older now than my father ever was.
这或许是我做的唯一一件有意义的事
This may be the only thing i do that matters.
打击犯罪二十年 毫无意义吗
20 years of fighting criminals amounts to nothing?
犯罪就像野草 阿尔弗雷德
Criminals are like weeds, Alfred.
除掉一个 又会在原地长出另一个
Pull one up, another grows in its place.
这关乎世界的未来
This is about the future of the world.
这是我的遗赠
This is my legacy.
我父亲曾让我坐在这里
My father sat me down right here.
告诉我韦恩家族是靠什么起家的
Told me what Wayne manor was built on.
铁路 房地产 还有石油
Railroads, real estates, and oil.
第一代和法国人做生意大赚了一笔
The first generation made their fortune trading with the French.
毛皮生意
Pelts and skins.
他们都是猎人
They were hunters.
所以韦恩家族会陨落
So falls the house of Wayne.
我们得等待更多证据
We gotta wait for more evidence,
但问题还在
but the question still remains,
他在哪
where is he?
如果超人没有参与其中
If superman was not involved,
如果他光明磊落 那为何自惨剧发生的那天起
if he's got nothing to hide, then why hasn't he been seen
一直没看到他现身
since the day of this tragedy?
你不能把矛头指向...
You can't point a finger and...
我什么都没指啊 沃伦 十根手指在这呢 看见没
I'm not pointing anything, Warren. Look. Ten fingers, see?
如果有罪犯...
If there is going to be a criminal...
黑夜已至
The night is here.
打扰下
Excuse me.
我是不是见过...
Don't I know...
注:改自小说《洛丽塔》中的句子
早晨就叫小露 穿便服时就叫露拉
Plain lo in the morning. Lola in slacks.
露易丝·莱恩
Lois Lane.
来看看风景
Mmm. Come see the view.
高度的秘诀
Now the secret to the height
在于建筑材料
is the building material.
这里用的是轻金属 所以在风中有点晃
It's light metals which sway a bit in the wind.
你对莱克斯集团的金属也有些了解 对吧 莱恩小姐
And you know something about lexcorp metals, don't you, miss Lane?
我已经查实了你的所作所为
I've proven what you've done.
你还真能折腾
Wow, you're feisty.
可惜 那一切都将随风而逝
Unfortunately, that will blow away.
就如沙漠中的沙子
Like sand in the desert.
你是个精神病
You're psychotic.
狭隘的头脑都是用
That is a three-syllable word
这个三音节词来描述伟大创想的
for any thought too big for little minds.
下个类别 圆圈
Hmm. Next category: Circles.
一圈一圈又一圈 他们到处找超人
Round and round and round they go to find superman.
搞错类别了 少年 应该是三角形
Wrong category, boy. No, no, triangles.
没错 欧几里得的三角不等式
Yes, euclid's triangle inequality.
任意两点之间的最短距离
The shortest distance between any two points
是直线
is a straight path.
我相信通向超人最直的线
And I believe the straightest path to superman
是一条非常小的路...
is a pretty little road...
叫露易丝·莱恩
Called Lois Lane.
你回来了
You came back.
少年 我们在这是不是有些问题啊
Boy, do we have problems up here!
关于世间邪恶的问题
The problem of... Of evil in the world.
关于至善的问题
The problem of absolute virtue.
我不会打残你 我要把你收监
I'll take you in without breaking you.
这更是你应得的
Which is more than you deserve.
关于你高高在上的问题
The problem of you on top of everything else.
你凌驾于一切之上
You above all.
因为神就是这样
Ah, because that's what god is.
荷鲁斯 阿波罗 耶和华 卡尔·艾尔
Horus. Apollo. Jehovah. Kal- El.
克拉克·约瑟夫·肯特
Clark Joseph Kent.
瞧 克拉克·乔 我们对神的称呼取决于我们的部族
See, what we call god depends upon our tribe, Clark-Joe.
因为神也分部族 神也选立场
Because god is tribal. God takes sides.
我小时候 天上可没人来干涉
No man in the sky intervened when I was a boy
我爸的拳头和憎恶 将我从中解救
to deliver me from daddy's fist and abominations. Mmm.
我早就明白了 如果神是全能的
I figured out way back, if god is all-powerful,
那他就不可能至善至美
he cannot be all-good.
如果他至善至美
And if he is all-good,
那他就不可能全能
then he cannot be all-powerful.
而这两者 你都不可能
And neither can you be.
他们需要亲眼看到
They need to see the fraud you are.
你的假象
With their eyes.
你手上的鲜血
The blood on your hands.
你干了什么
What have you done?
今晚他们就会看到
And tonight, they will.
没错 我的朋友 因为你要去赴约
Yes. Because you, my friend, have a date.
要飞越海湾
Across the bay.
他积聚了两年的恨意 是时候爆发了
Ripe fruit, his hate. Two years growing.
不过逼他爆发 倒没怎么费力
But it did not take much to push him over, actually.
红色小标注 大爆炸
Little red notes, big bang.
你害死了你的家人
You let your family die!
现在你要飞到他那里
And now you will fly to him.
和他战斗
And you will battle him.
至死方休
To the death.
黑与蓝 对决之夜
Black and blue. Fight night!
世界历史上最伟大的角斗士对决
The greatest gladiator match in the history of the world.
天神对凡人
God versus man.
白昼对黑夜
Day versus night.
氪星之子对哥谭蝙蝠
Son of Krypton versus bat of Gotham.
你觉得我会为了你 而与他一战?
You think I'll fight him for you?
没错 我认为你会为了你生命中的
Yes, I do. I think you will fight-fight-fight
那位特别的女士战斗 战斗 战斗
for that special lady in your life.
她在地面很安全 而你呢
She's safe on the ground. How about you?
快说到了 不过我说的不是露易丝
Close, but I am not talking about Lois.
不是她 每个男孩的特别的女士都是母亲
No. Every boy's special lady is his mother.
玛莎 玛莎 玛莎
Martha, Martha, Martha.
飞天恶魔的母亲一定是个女巫
Why, the mother of a flying demon must be a witch.
对女巫的刑罚 是什么来着
The punishment for witches, what is that?
没错 被火烧死
That's right. Death by fire.
她在哪
Where is she?
我不知道 我不会让他们告诉我
I don't know! I would not let them tell me!
你要是杀了我 玛莎就会死
If you kill me, Martha dies.
如果你飞走 玛莎也会死
And if you fly away, mmm, Martha also dies.
但你要是杀了那蝙蝠...
But if you kill the bat...
玛莎就能活下来
Martha lives.
这就对了
There we go.
现在神都屈服于我的意志了
And now god bends to my will.
现在摄像机在你的飞船里等待着
Ooh, now the cameras are waiting at your ship.
等待着让全世界看到神的缺陷
For the world to see the holes in the holy.
没错 全能的神在需要之时
Yes, the almighty comes clean
便会尽显他的肮脏
about how dirty he is when it counts.
想救玛莎
To save Martha,
就把蝙蝠的头带给我
bring me the head of the bat.
圣母啊 你能看看时间吗
Mother of god, would you look at the time?
你到这里时 还有一个小时
When you came here, you had an hour.
现在更少了
Now it's less.
在现场的是布鲁克·鲍德温
Brooke Baldwin is on the scene.
布鲁克 直播交给你 你看到什么了
Brooke, you're live on the air. What are you seeing?
飞船那边有状况
There's something happening at the ship.
它在发出大量能量波
It's sending massive power surges.
警方的直升机已包围该区域
Police helicopters surrounding the area.
他们在管制中心的周围设了路障
They've created a barricade around this containment center.
我们正试图靠近一点
And we're trying to get a little bit closer here
来搞清楚是怎么回事
to find out what's going on.
这里混乱不堪 你们能看到那道闪电
It is absolute chaos. You can see that lightning,
还有那些电波
those surges of electricity.
它们似乎每分钟都在变得更为猛烈
They seem to be getting stronger by the minute.
去星球日报
Daily planet.
露易丝
Lois.
我必须去哥谭 说服他帮助我
I have to go to Gotham to convince him to help me.
谁
Who?
否则他就得死
Or he has to die.
克拉克
Clark.
这世上没人能一直善良下去
No one stays good in this world.
但截至目前 这座城市的大部分地区仍处于停电状态
But as of right now, much of the city remains in the dark tonight.
那么多混乱 那么多让人费解的事 都在今晚的大都会发生了
Much chaos. Much confusing happening on the streets of Metropolis tonight.
直升机仍包围着该区域
Those helicopters are still surrounding the area.
我不知道你们能否看到那些闪电...
I don't know if you can still see those bolts of lightning...
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
一则新消息
来自 布鲁斯·韦恩
男孩也会分享
破解了卢瑟的硬盘 发现了你的照片
但它并不属于你
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
它就是你
你是谁
你到过哪
莱克斯集团  超人类研究
你是谁
它就是你
_闪_监控_录像_01
_海_研究船_231113
2400小时又2分钟 对象正在迅速衰弱
2400 hours and 2 minutes. Subject declining rapidly.
所有程序上的干预手段都失败了
All procedural interventions have failed.
结果
Outcome
将是死亡
will be death.
塞拉斯·斯通医生暂停了所有临床协议
Dr. Silas stone suspending all clinical protocol.
美国政府 对象6-19-82 已成功激活
Us gov, object 6-19-82 is successfully activated.
我要一架直升机去哥谭
I need a chopper to Gotham.
打电话给直升机场
Call the heliport.
直升机? 我们连自行车都快承担不起了
Chopper? We can barely afford a bicycle.
你想追新闻?
You wanna chase a story?
去飞船那
Go to the ship.
超人可能已经在那了
Superman's probably there already.
佩里 这不是为了新闻
Perry, it's not for a story.
珍妮 给她弄一架直升机去哥谭
Jenny, get her a chopper to Gotham.
别停到停机坪 给我停到楼顶
And forget the heliport. Put it on the goddamn roof.
停到楼顶 露易丝
On the roof, Lois!
我们去哪
Where are we headed?
那边
There!
我来了
Well, here I am.
布鲁斯 别这样
Bruce. Please.
我错了 你得听我说
I was wrong. You have to listen to me.
莱克斯想要我们...
Lex wants us to...
你不明白
You don't understand.
没时间了
There's no time!
我明白
I understand.
待着别动
Stay down!
要是我动真格 你早就没命了
If I wanted it, you'd be dead already.
吸进去
Breathe it in.
那就是恐惧
That's fear.
你并不勇敢
You're not brave.
人类才勇敢
Men are brave.
监管之人 谁来监管
我打赌你父母曾教导你说 你的存在是有意义的
I bet your parents taught you that you mean something.
说你来到这里是有原因的
That you're here for a reason.
而我父母教了我不同的一课
My parents taught me a different lesson,
他们完全毫无缘由地
dying in the gutter
死在了排水沟边
for no reason at all.
他们教导我 只有你逼迫这个世界
They taught me the world only makes sense
它才会变得合理
if you force it to.
你从来都不是神
You were never a god.
你甚至从来都不是人类
You were never even a man.
你是在让他杀掉玛莎
You're letting him kill Martha.
什么意思
What does that mean?
你为什么提那个名字
Why did you say that name?
找到他
Find him.
救出
Save
玛莎
Martha.
你为什么提那个名字
Why did you say that name?
玛莎 你为什么提那个名字
Martha! Why did you say that name?
克拉克 住手
Clark! Stop!
求你了 住手
Please! Stop!
你为什么提那个名字
Why did you say that name?
那是他母亲的名字
It's his mother's name!
It's his mother's name.
我们没得到任何答案
We're not getting any answers.
我们仍在管制中心外面
We're still right outside the containment center.
情况非常危险
A dangerous situation.
军方和警员
Military and police personnel
正在包围该区域
surrounding the area.
卢瑟
Luthor.
他想要你的命来换她的命
He wanted your life for hers.
她时间不多了
She's losing time.
那艘侦查飞船似乎在吸取城市的电力
The scout ship seems to be drawing power from the city.
肯定是莱克斯干的
It's got to be Lex.
飞船那边需要你 我会找到她的
They need you at that ship. I'll find her.
- 我母亲需要我 - 等等
- My mother needs me. - Wait.
我向你保证
I'll make you a promise.
今晚玛莎不会死
Martha won't die tonight.
韦恩老爷
Master Wayne.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
抱歉 我偷听了
Uh, I'm sorry for listening in,
不过我追踪俄国人的手机
but I've tracked the Russian's phone
追踪到了一间靠近港口的仓库
to a warehouse near the port.
已帮你锁定直飞路线
You're locked onto it.
我不值得你这样 阿尔弗雷德
I don't deserve you, Alfred.
没错 先生 你是不值得
No, sir. You don't.
恐怕要说再见了
I'm afraid this is goodbye.
注:改自雷蒙·钱德勒小说《漫长的告别》中的
"To say goodbye is to die a little"
我们每说一次再见 你就离死亡更近了一点
And every time we say goodbye, you die a little.
- 把它打下来 - 打啊 快打
- Take it down. - Go! Go!
阿尔弗雷德 你来操控
You have to take it, Alfred.
好的
Rght.
开启无人机模式
Commencing drone mode.
热成像显示
Thermal imaging is showing me
三楼有二十四个敌人
two dozen hostiles on the third floor.
不如我把你放在二楼吧
Why don't I drop you off on the second?
放下
Drop it.
我说了放下
I said drop it!
我会杀了她
I'll kill her.
相信我 我会动手的
Believe me, I'll do it.
我相信你
I believe you.
没事了 我是你儿子的一个朋友
It's okay. I'm a friend of your son's.
我猜到了 你也有披风
I figured. The cape.
注:改自《爱丽丝梦游仙境》中总说自己迟到了的白兔的话
迟到了 迟到了 小白兔说道
"Late, late," says the white rabbit.
离重生还有40秒
40 seconds to animation.
对吗 小白兔
Right, wabbit?
你没招了 也没时间了
Out of tricks, out of time.
还少了蝙蝠的头
And one bat head short.
离重生还有30秒
30 seconds to animation.
厨师来电了
That'll be the cook.
失陪下
Excuse me.
哥谭烤肉 全熟
Gotham roast. Well done.
你好 爆坏消息吧
Hello. Break the bad news.
我更想当面爆
I'd rather do the breaking in person.
离重生还有20秒
20 seconds to animation.
你输了
You've lost.
我不知道怎么输
I don't know how to lose.
你会学会的
You'll learn.
我会学会的
I'll learn.
我不恨罪恶之人
I don't hate the sinner.
- 我恨的是罪恶本身 - 离重生还有10秒
- I hate the sin. - 10 seconds to animation.
而你的罪恶 我的朋友 就是你的存在
And yours, my friend, is existing.
我不能让你赢
I cannot let you win.
我给了那蝙蝠一战的机会
I gave the bat a fighting chance to do it,
但他不够强
but he was not strong enough.
所以 如果凡人杀不了天神
So, if man won't kill god...
二 一
...two, one.
那就让魔鬼代劳吧
...the devil will do it!
佩里
Perry!
好了 各位保持冷静
All right. Stay calm, everybody!
我们收到报告称这座城市
We're getting reports there are total blackouts
从北部到西北部都完全停电了
in the north and to the northwest of the city.
联邦政府正在试图查明
Federal authorities are trying to determine
这是否是一次大规模恐怖袭击的一部分
if this is part of a larger terrorist attack.
古老的氪星畸形生物
Ancient Kryptonian deformity.
吾血之血
Blood of my blood.
生来就为了毁灭你
Born to destroy you.
这就是  你的毁灭日
Your doomsday.
现在 神
Now god is good
死定了
as dead.
总统来电了
Potus joining.
总统先生
Mr. president.
那到底是什么东西 卡尔文
What the hell is it, Calvin?
这些是来自大都会市中心莱克斯集团
These are live images from the top
塔楼楼顶的直播画面
of the lexcorp tower in downtown Metropolis.
军用飞机已抵达现场
Military aircraft are on the scene.
- 你受伤了吗 女士 - 我没事
- Are you hurt, ma'am? - I'm okay.
那就好  你会没事的 好吗
Good. You're gonna be all right, okay?
这个东西就在几分钟前
This thing emerged from the Kryptonian
从氪星飞船坠毁点出现了
crash site just moments ago.
不过幸好市中心核心区的人都下班了
Thankfully though, the work day is over in the downtown core.
那里几乎没人了
It's nearly empty.
现在军用飞机 那些是阿帕奇直升机
Now military aircraft. Those are apache helicopters.
它们刚刚到达 画面...
They have now just arrived. The images that...
我们...我们刚与大都会新闻8台失去了通讯连接
We've, uh... We just lost connection with Metropolis 8 news.
现在不清楚那里发生了什么
Now, it's not clear what just happened.
那边怎么了 阿尔弗雷德
What's happening there, Alfred?
怎么说好呢
How best to describe it?
大都会空域已被暂时关闭
Metropolis airspace has been closed briefly.
我能打扰下吗
Excuse me?
我们恳请您待在座位上
We kindly ask that you stay in your seats.
我能打扰下吗
Excuse me?
普林斯小姐
Miss prince?
长官 看 他们已离开城市
Sir. Look, they've cleared the city.
他好像在把它带入太空
Looks like he's taking it into space.
我们可以直接按下红色按钮了 总统先生
We can go straight to key red, Mr. president.
还不行 你疯了吗
Not yet. Are you crazy?
他们飞得够高了 我们能用核弹攻击他们
They're high enough that we can nuke 'em
不会有一人伤亡 长官
with no casualties, sir.
会有一人 总统先生 超人
One casualty, Mr. president. Superman.
愿上帝宽恕我们所有人
God have mercy on us all.
- 已插入钥匙 - 已插入钥匙
- Key is hot. - Key is hot.
红鸟已就位 等待发射 长官
Red birds are armed to deploy, sir.
发射吧
Fire at will.
三 二 一
Three, two, one...
天啊
Oh, god.
一号抛体 撞击了
Projectile 1. Impact.
大都会东部  斯特瑞克之岛
Stryker's island, east of Metropolis.
那里无人居住
That's uninhabited.
二号抛体
Projectile 2...
无明显重返大气层迹象
No apparent reentry.
二号抛体呢
Projectile 2?
超人 总统先生 二号抛体是超人
Superman, Mr. president. Projectile 2 was superman.
长官
Sir.
它在移动
It's moving.
冲击波越来越强了
The shockwaves are getting stronger.
我们每击中它一次 都会让它变得更强
Every time we hit it, we make it more powerful.
我们不能攻击
We can't attack.
卡尔文 你在说什么
What are you saying, Calvin?
我在说它是杀不死的
I'm saying it's unkillable.
韦恩老爷 接收得到我的信号吗
Master Wayne, are you receiving me?
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
它是氪星生物
It's Kryptonian.
只有氪石武器才能杀死它
Only kryptonite weapons can kill it.
也许吧 如果你有剩余的话
They might. If you had any left.
我还剩一发氪石弹
I got one round left.
那根矛 阿尔弗雷德 那根矛 是纯氪石做的
The spear. Alfred, the spear. It's pure kryptonite.
它在哥谭
It's back in Gotham.
如果我能刺穿它的皮肤 那根矛就能杀死它
If I can penetrate the skin, the spear will kill it.
理论上是这样
It would in theory.
我得引它追着我回到哥谭
I've gotta get it to chase me back to the city.
回到氪石那里
Back to the kryptonite.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
你为什么把它带回这座城市
Why did you bring him back to the city?
这个港口已被废弃
The port is abandoned.
这里有能杀死它的武器
There's a weapon here that can kill it.
你找到那根矛了吗
Did you find the spear?
我有点忙
I've been a little busy.
这个东西 这个生物 似乎是靠吸收能量活着的
This thing, this creature, seems to feed on energy.
这个东西来自另一个世界
This thing is from another world.
我的世界
My world.
我以前杀过来自其他世界的东西
I've killed things from other worlds before.
她跟你一伙的吗
Is she with you?
我还以为她跟你一伙的
I thought she was with you.
克拉克
Clark!
克拉克 你没事吧
Clark! Are you all right?
我爱你
I love you.
不行 不行 克拉克 你不能去
No. No, Clark, you can't.
这里是我的世界
This is my world.
不行 克拉克 别去
No, Clark, don't.
你就是我的世界
You are my world.
不行
No.
求你了 克拉克
Please. Clark!
超人之死
恐惧之夜 失落之晨
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭一役中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
星球日报记者
克拉克·肯特
在报道哥谭之战中遇害
莱克斯·卢瑟因涉嫌国会大厦炸弹袭击被捕
嗨
Hi.
克拉克之前把这个寄了过来 想给你个惊喜
Clark had this sent here, so he could surprise you.
注:出自《圣经》以赛亚书26章19节
死者要复活
"The dead shall live.
尸首要兴起
"My slain shall rise again.
睡在尘埃的啊 要醒起歌唱
"Awake and sing, ye that dwell in dust.
因你的甘露好像菜蔬上的甘露
"For thy dew is like the dew of morning.
地也要交出死人来
"And the earth shall give birth to her dead."
我需要搭车回家一趟
I need a ride back to the house.
我忘带支票本了 还要付钱给殡葬承办人呢
I forgot my checkbook to pay the funeral director.
他们说全都付清了
They said it's all taken care of.
谁付的
By whom?
匿名捐赠者
Anonymous donor.
东边的那些表演只是在下葬一副空棺材
All those circuses back east burying an empty box.
他们不知道如何缅怀他
They don't know how to honor him,
只能当做军人
except as a soldier.
他活着时
I've failed him
我辜负了他
in life.
他死后 我不会再辜负他
I won't fail him in death.
帮我找到其他像你这样的人
Help me find the others like you.
也许他们不希望被找到
Perhaps they don't want to be found.
他们会的 他们还要战斗
They will. And they'll fight.
我们必须联手
We have to stand together.
一百年前 我离开了人类
100 years ago, I walked away from mankind.
远离了一个世纪的恐怖万象
From a century of horrors.
人类创造了一个不可能联手的世界
Man made a world where standing together is impossible.
人类依然优秀
Men are still good.
我们争斗 厮杀
We fight. We kill.
我们相互背叛
We betray one another.
但我们能重新开始
But we can rebuild.
我们能做得更好
We can do better.
我们会的
We will.
我们必须如此
We have to.
如果你在寻找他的丰碑 看看你的周围吧
其他像我一样的人
The others like me.
为什么你说他们必须战斗
Why did you say they'll have to fight?
只是一种感觉
Just a feeling.
囚犯 A-C-23-19-40
Prisoner A-C-23-19-40.
监狱长想跟你谈话 站起来
The warden wants to speak to you, so stand to your feet.
我再说一遍
I'm gonna say this one more time.
监狱长想跟你谈话 站起来
The warden wants to speak to you, so stand to your feet.
转过身 面朝墙
Turn around and face the wall.
前额靠住墙
Place your forehead against the wall.
双手放背后
Put your hands behind your back,
我进来好控制你
so that I can come in and restrain you.
无论你做什么 无论你去哪里
Whatever you do, wherever you go,
我都会盯着你
I'll be watching you.
看看我们啊
Look at us.
一切就是这样分崩离析的
This is how it all caves in.
韦恩庄园的文明被丢弃了
Civilization on the Wayne manor's out the window.
但是谁会相信我呢 我...
But who would believe me? I...
我疯了
I'm insane.
我都没法受审
I'm not even fit to stand trial.
没错
That's right.
悉心照料精神病患者的医院有不少
We have hospitals that treat the mentally ill with compassion.
但那里不是你要去的地方
But that's not where you're going.
我已给你安排好转去哥谭的阿卡姆疯人院
I arranged for you to get transferred to arkham asylum in Gotham.
我在那里还有些朋友
I still have some friends there.
他们在等着你
They're expecting you.
但钟声已被敲响
But the bell's already been rung.
他们已经听到了
And they've heard it.
在黑暗之中
Out in the dark.
在群星之中
Among the stars.
注:改自1939年版《绿野仙踪》插曲《Ding-Dong!The Witch Is Dead》
叮咚 神已经死了
Ding dong, the god is dead.
但钟声是收不回的
But a bell cannot be unrung!
他饿了
He's hungry.
他找到我们了
He's found us.
他要来了
And he's coming!
译者:微博@Emtee
微博@字母编辑
初校:微博@字母编辑
微博@正义联盟实习生
微博@Cumberkid
二校:微博@正义联盟实习生
总校:微博@Emtee
鸣谢:微博@字母编辑
微博@正义联盟实习生
微博@Cumberkid